import { SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

const path = "@/assets/images/pastquestions-figures/integratedscience/integratedscienceA/integratedscience-"

export const INTEGRATEDSCIENCEA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. Gum bleeding in humans is caused by the deficiency of ...................",
A: "vitamin A.",
B: "vitamin B.",
C: "vitamin C.",
D: "vitamin D.",
answer: "C. vitamin C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. Kerosene, diesel and bitumen are obtained from crude oil by a process called",
A: "cracking.",
B: "chromatography.",
C: "sublimation.",
D: "fractional distillation.",
answer: "D. fractional distillation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. A machine is classified as a first class level when the ...................",
A: "pivot is between the load and effort.",
B: "load is between the effort and pivot.",
C: "pivot is beyond the effort.",
D: "load is before the pivot and effort.",
answer: "A. pivot is between the load and effort",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. Which of the following signs is associated with parturition in a cattle?",
A: "The belly becomes distended and drops.",
B: "The vulva becomes contracted.",
C: "Difficulty in urination.",
D: "The udder becomes smaller.",
answer: "A. The belly becomes distended and drops",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. In the digestive system of a mammal, fatty acids and glycerol are absorbed in the .........",
A: "caecum.",
B: "duodenum.",
C: "ileum.",
D: "stomach.",
answer: "C. ileum",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. An ion X has 16 protons, 17 neutrons and 18 electrons. Which of the following statements about X is correct? X is ..........................",
A: "a cation with one positive charge.",
B: "a cation with two negative charges.",
C: "an anion with two negative charges.",
D: "an anion with one negative charge.",
answer: "C. an anion with two negative charges",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. A wet piece of cloth dries faster when spread than folded because the......................",
A: "temperature will be even in the cloth.",
B: "water will drip out of the cloth faster.",
C: "large surface area will aid evaporation of water.",
D: "water will be distributed evenly in the cloth.",
answer: "C. large surface area will aid evaporation of water",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Fertilization in humans usually occurs in the ..........................",
A: "ovary.",
B: "oviduct.",
C: "uterus.",
D: "vagina.",
answer: "B. oviduct",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. In the preparation of local soap, the ash of plantain peels is added to the palm oil in order to .......................",
A: "thicken the oil.",
B: "give color to the soap.",
C: "provide alkali.",
D: "give the soap a pleasant smell.",
answer: "C. provide alkali",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Which of the following management practices ensure the raising of healthy chicks? \nI. Controlling of human traffic to the brooder house. \n II. Debeaking chicks when they are two weeks old. \n III. Ensuring good ventilation in the brooder house. \nIV. Visiting older chicks first before the brooding chicks.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "III and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "C. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Consider the energy transformation below: Electrical energy > magnetic energy > kinetic energy > sound energy. In which of the following devices will the energy transformation occur?",
A: "Electric bell",
B: "Electric fan",
C: "Electric kettle",
D: "Transformer",
answer: "A. Electric bell",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. In flowering plants, mineral salts are transported through the  .............................",
A: "cambium.",
B: "phloem.",
C: "stomata.",
D: "xylem.",
answer: "D. xylem",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
instruction: "The diagram below is an illustration of laboratory apparatus. Use it to answer Questions 13 and 14. [[ Diagram ]]]",
id: "question13",
question: "13. The apparatus illustrated is a.....................................",
A: "stirring rod.",
B: "retort stand.",
C: "pair of tongs.",
D: "test tube holder.",
answer: "D. test tube holder",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. The apparatus is used to.............................",
A: "crush solids.",
B: "hold objects in firm position.",
C: "take small quantities of substances.",
D: "hold a test tube during heating.",
answer: "D. hold a test tube during heating",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. The frictional force between two bodies depends on the....................",
A: "area of the surfaces in contact.",
B: "speed at which the bodies are moving.",
C: "nature of the surfaces of the bodies in contact.",
D: "moment of the bodies in contact.",
answer: "C. nature of the surfaces of the bodies in contact",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. Which of the following statements about anaerobic respiration is correct?",
A: "Oxygen gas is released.",
B: "Oxygen gas is used up.",
C: "Glucose is broken down.",
D: "Carbon dioxide and water are produced.",
answer: "C. Glucose is broken down",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Consider the chemical equation below: CH3COOH + C2H5OH > CH3COOC2H5 + H2O This equation represents..........................",
A: "an addition reaction.",
B: "a neutralization reaction.",
C: "an esterification reaction.",
D: "a saponification reaction.",
answer: "C. an esterification reaction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Which of the following methods could be used to control water logging in soils?",
A: "Drainage.",
B: "Irrigation.",
C: "Leaching.",
D: "Mulching.",
answer: "A. Drainage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. When an n-p-n transistor is used as a simple amplifier, the base-emitter junction is \n I. forward biased \nII. reverse biased \nIII. Neutral \n Which of the following statements is/are correct?",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "III only",
D: "I and III only",
answer: "A. I only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Which of the following movements occur when the arm of a human is bent?",
A: "Biceps relaxes and triceps contracts",
B: "Biceps contracts and triceps relaxes",
C: "Both biceps and triceps relax",
D: "Both biceps and triceps contract",
answer: "B. Biceps contracts and triceps relaxes",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. Chemical properties of organic compounds are determined by the.................",
A: "functional group.",
B: "substituent group.",
C: "number of hydrogen atoms.",
D: "number of carbon atoms.",
answer: "A. functional group",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. A small metal block is 12 cm long, 6.0 cm high and 4.0 cm wide. If it has a mass of 1.5 kg, determine its density.",
A: "0.2 g cm2",
B: "5.2 g cm-3",
C: "192.0 g cm-3",
D: "288.0 g cm-3",
answer: "B. 5",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. In a certain breed of cattle, black fur was dominant over white fur. Determine the possible genotype of a cattle with black fur which produces a white calf.",
A: "BB",
B: "BW",
C: "Bw",
D: "Bb",
answer: "C. Bw",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. Which of the following gases is environmentally friendly when present in large quantities?",
A: "Methane",
B: "Nitrogen",
C: "Carbon monoxide",
D: "Hydrogen sulphide",
answer: "B. Nitrogen",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. The difficulty encountered by pigs in loosing body heat through perspiration could be overcome by........................",
A: "deworming the pigs.",
B: "using dry bedding in the sty.",
C: "providing fresh clean water in the sty.",
D: "avoiding overcrowding of pigs in the sty.",
answer: "D. avoiding overcrowding of pigs in the sty",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. Regular reflection of light occurs when the reflector is........................",
A: "smooth with black surface.",
B: "smooth with shiny surface.",
C: "rough with black surface.",
D: "rough with white surface.",
answer: "B. smooth with shiny surface",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. The main advantage of sexual reproduction over asexual reproduction is that sexual reproduction ....................",
A: "takes place at all times.",
B: "is quicker than asexual reproduction.",
C: "brings about variation than asexual reproduction.",
D: "provides more offspring than asexual reproduction.",
answer: "C. brings about variation than asexual reproduction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. Maize is a cereal because it ..............................",
A: "produces seeds.",
B: "has narrow leaves.",
C: "has long roots.",
D: "grows in marginal soil.",
answer: "A. produces seeds",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Which of the following pairs of elements can combine to form an ionic compound?",
A: "C and O",
B: "Al and Mg",
C: "H and S",
D: "Cu and O",
answer: "D. Cu and O",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Which of the following characteristics can be used to distinguish between the same note played on a piano and an organ?",
A: "Beat",
B: "Loudness",
C: "Pitch",
D: "Quality",
answer: "D. Quality",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. The relative proportion of various particle sizes in a given soil sample is called..................",
A: "coarseness.",
B: "profile.",
C: "structure.",
D: "texture.",
answer: "D. texture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. An object placed between a converging lens and it’s principle focus produces an image which is always I. erect II. virtual III. real IV. magnified",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and IV only",
C: "I, II and IV only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "C. I, II and IV only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Which of the following substances is excreted by the skin of human?",
A: "Water and urea only",
B: "Salts and urea only",
C: "Salts and water only",
D: "Salts, urea and water only",
answer: "D. Salts, urea and water only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. The general molecular formula of alkanes is .............................",
A: "CnH2n.",
B: "CnH2n – 2.",
C: "CnH2n – 1.",
D: "CnH2n + 2.",
answer: "D. CnH2n + 2",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Transfusion of incompatible blood into a patient may lead to...........................",
A: "production of antigens.",
B: "formation of clots of blood.",
C: "rapture of red blood cells.",
D: "reduction in the number of white blood cells.",
answer: "A. production of antigens",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Yam is propagated through its tuber because the tuber bears...................",
A: "buds.",
B: "internodes.",
C: "nodes.",
D: "adventitious roots.",
answer: "A. buds",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Which of the following salts can cause temporary hardness of water?",
A: "CaSO4",
B: "MgCl2",
C: "Fe2(SO4)3",
D: "Ca(HCO3)",
answer: "D. Ca(HCO3)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. Mercury is used as a thermometric liquid because it ...........................",
A: "has a low heat capacity.",
B: "is colourless.",
C: "does not vapourise.",
D: "has a high density.",
answer: "C. does not vapourise",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. Tsetsefly is the vector of the organism that causes.........................",
A: "elephantiasis.",
B: "malaria.",
C: "sleeping sickness.",
D: "river blindness.",
answer: "C. sleeping sickness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. Policies aimed at conserving natural resources should ensure that the....................",
A: "resources of the country are exported for foreign exchange.",
B: "citizens of the country help to keep the environment clean.",
C: "resources to sustain the present and future generations are properly managed.",
D: "resources are managed such that ever citizen can obtain a fair share of the national cake.",
answer: "C. resources to sustain the present and future generations are properly managed",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
instruction: "The diagram below is an illustration of an agricultural tool. Use it to answer Questions 41 and 42. [[ Diagram ]]]",
id: "question41",
question: "41. The tool illustrated is ........................",
A: "sickle.",
B: "shear.",
C: "rake.",
D: "mattock.",
answer: "C. rake",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. The tool is used to......................",
A: "lift and turn the soil.",
B: "turn compost heap.",
C: "uproot small stumps.",
D: "level and gather rubbish.",
answer: "D. level and gather rubbish",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following processes in living organisms takes place b diffusion? \nI. Removal of waste products from plants and animals.    \nII. Absorption of mineral salts by plants from the soil through root hair cells.  \nIII. Digested food, mineral salts and get into the blood stream from the ileum of a mammal.  \nIV. Absorption of water in the large intestine of mammals.",
A: "I and II only.",
B: "III and IV only.",
C: "I, II and III only.",     
D: "II, III and IV only.",
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. The power rating of an electric stove is 750 W. Determine the current flowing through it if it’s resistance is 15 ?",
A: "7.07 A",
B: "50.00 A",
C: "62.50 A",
D: "6250.00 A",
answer: "A. 7",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. In an ecological study, small animals such as ants found on leaves and crevices can be collected by ........................",
A: "pooter.",
B: "quadrat.",
C: "transect.",
D: "sweep net.",
answer: "A. pooter",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. Which of the following factors account for the rate of production of hydrogen in the reaction below: 2HCl + Mg > H2 + MgCl2  \nI. Concentration of the acid. \nII. Surface area of the magnesium. \nIII. Temperature. \nIV. Pressure of the atmosphere.",
A: "I and II only.",
B: "III and IV only.",
C: "I, II and III only.",
D: "II, III and IV only.",
answer: "C. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. A bell jar contains a ringing bell. As the air inside is pumped out, the sound intensity gradually decreases because........................",
A: "a medium is needed for sound transmission.",
B: "the sound has turned into stationary waves.",
C: "the sound cannot pass through the solid bell jar.",
D: "the air inside the jar is heated.",
answer: "A. a medium is needed for sound transmission",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Which of the following activities are performed when a person is involved in an electric shock? \n I. Using a dry material to put off the main source of electric supply \nII. Covering the victim with extra clothing for warmth \nIII. Massaging the victim \n IV. Administering artificial respiration to sustain the victim",
A: "I and II only.",
B: "III and IV only.",
C: "I, II and III only.",
D: "I, III and IV only.",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Dipping is an important husbandry practice in farm animal production because it",
A: "controls endoparasites.",
B: "prevents bacterial attack.",
C: "controls ectoparasites.",
D: "improves upon growth rate.",
answer: "C. controls ectoparasites",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. The seed of a flowing plant imbibes water through the ..................",
A: "hilum.",
B: "integument.",
C: "micropyle.",
D: "testa",
answer: "C. micropyle",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},



]